Akash Rajmane Full Stack Developer

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/akash-rajmane 🜎 https://github.com/Akash-Rajmane

https://akash-rajmane-portfolio.netlify.app/

Experienced Software Developer with a passion for creating immersive user experience. I have strong knowledge in ReactJS, NextJS, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ECMAScript latest versions), Redux, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, MySQL and I am aware of Web Content Accessibility Guidelines, optimization techniques, React Profiling, AWS S3 and AWS EC2. I also have a good sense of design and a willingness to learn new things.

Skills

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | TypeScript | ReactJS | NextJS | Redux | Redux Toolkit | D3JS | SCSS | Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS | Responsive Web Design | NodeJS | ExpressJS | MongoDB | MySQL | Storybook | AWS S3 | AWS EC2

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, MIT Academy of Engineering CGPA: 8.31

2015 - 2019

HSC, Dattakala International School & Jr. College

2015

Percentage: 72.92

SSC, Sadashivrao Mane Vidyalaya

2013

Percentage: 94

Professional Experience

Associate Software Engineer, Tech Mahindra

12/2021 - 03/2023

Tech Stack: ReactJS, HTML, SCSS, TypeScript, D3JS, Storybook, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, NPM

- Worked as a Software Developer on the development of reusable components and showcasing the developed components in the storybook.
- Learned D3JS, TypeScript and implemented these concepts to develop reusable components which reduced the creation of new components by 70%.
- Developed new features for the components, resolved issues in the components.

Internship & Certifications

React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB - The MERN Fullstack Guide, *Udemy*

React The Complete Guide, Udemy

Newton School Coding Bootcamp, Newton School

06/2021 - 11/2021

Sharpener Coding Bootcamp, Shapener Tech

09/2023 – present

Created projects like ecommerce website, expense tracker, mailboxclient.

Projects

Expesne Tracker

Technical Stack Used: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React-Router-Dom, Razorpay Payment Gateway, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, Sequelize, JWT Authentication, nodemailer, AWS S3.

Features:

- User signup, login, reset password, logout and responsive web design.
- Add, Delete Expense. User can see Full Expense Report.
- Premium users can download Full Expense Report, see daily/weekly/monthly/yearly Expense Report, see previously downloaded files, see Expense Leaderboard.

FavPlaces 🗆

Technical Stack Used: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React-Router-Dom, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, JWT Authentication, Google Maps API

Features:

- User signup, login, logout and responsive web design.
- User can Add, Edit, Delete places.
- User can see other users and their saved places.
- Automatic generation of map on inputting address

Students Manager 🛮

Technical Stack Used: ReactJS, Typescript, HTML, SCSS, JavaScript, React- Router-Dom, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB

Features:

- Add, Edit, Delete student, Delete all students, Students Statistics.
- Sort students according to marks or attendance, download the students data from leaderboard.
- Show students data in the form of card, search students by name or roll number.
- It is a progressive, responsive web app.